<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resume on Ashok Anand B</title>
    <link>https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resume on Ashok Anand B</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/education/</guid>
      <description>San Diego State Univeristy:
Masters in Big Data Analytics (May 2021)
Coursework: Machine learning Engineering, Big Data Analytics Platforms, Python Scripting, Business Analytics, Database Theory , Enterprise Data Management, Statistical Analysis, Statistical methods in Text Analysis. Dayananda Sagar College Of Engineering:
Bachelors in Engineering (June 2019)
Coursework: Probability and Statistics, Management Information Systems, Programming in Python, Data Structures and programming in C, CAD/CAM and Robotics. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional experience</title>
      <link>https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/experience/</guid>
      <description>Associate Data Analyst at EnEx Tech Solutions: (May 2018-July 2019)
  Implemented analytical intelligence for clients, part of a team focused on growing businesses through customer churn rate predictions on python and targeted marketing.
  Development and maintenance of ETL pipelines for client databases. Used logical database design and RDBMS concepts to improve database designs reducing data load delays exponentially.
  Writing SQL queries using multiple joins and subqueries to migrate data from databases to SAS and Tableau for creating dashboards and projected financial reports, as well as statistical analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ashok-ab4.github.io/portfolio/resume/skills/</guid>
      <description>Programming languages:  Python R C++ Java  Business Intelligence and visualization tools:  Tableau PowerBI Google datastudio Salesforce analytics Python - matplotlib, seaborn  Database techonlogies:  MSSQL server MYSQL Oracle PostgreSQL  Big Data Technologies:  Spark Hadoop MongoDB Hive  Machine Learning:  Pandas Numpy Scikit-Learn Deep Learning - Keras, Tensorflow, Pytorch Text analysis - Spacy, NLTK BeautifulSoup  Misc:  Git AWS Google Cloud platform Microsoft office - Excel (advanced lookup, pivot tables, etc) IDE - Jupyter, Pycharm, Google Colab, RStudio, Visual Studio  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
